[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
In this module we talked about a notion of collaborative filtering and
在这个模块中 我们讨论了协同过滤的基本概念
a couple different recommender systems for implementing that idea where we leverage
和一系列不同的推荐系统 能够让我们
the types of other products people purchased to recommend other products.
通过人们的购买记录 来进行产品推荐
And we explored this notion of having some set of customers and
我们研究了 在一些消费者和产品中
products and understanding relationships between these in the context of
在产品推荐系统的背景下 如何理解他们直接的关系
product recommendation tasks, thinking about movie recommendation.
回想一下电影推荐系统
And in the IPython notebook you guys explore this very concretely with
和你们在Ipython Notebook里面 研究的
an implementation of a song recommender.
音乐推荐系统
Once again, let's revisit this machine learning workflow, but
让我们重新回顾一下 机器学习的工作流程
in the context of recommender systems.
在我们推荐系统中
In this case, what's our training data?
什么是我们的训练数据
Well it's our user,
是我们的客户
product, ratings, table.
产品 评分 这个表格
And what we're gonna do is we're gonna extract some set of features,
我们所做的是 就是抽出一些特征
which in this case are a user ID, product ID pair
比如说UserID用户ID product ID产品ID 这一对
And the goal here is to predict the rating that some user would give to some product.
目标是 预测这些用户会对这些产品所给出的评分
So user ID, product ID, rating.
所以说 用户ID 产品ID 评分
So this is our predicted rating, y hat.
这就是我们的预测评分 也就是y帽
If we're specifically looking, and I guess I, sorry,
如果我们仔细看 抱歉
I should mention that, what is the model that we're looking at?
我应该说道 我们这个模型应该看的是什么
The model is, for example,
这个模型 举个例子
we talked about many different models but the one we're gonna talk about quite
我们提到了很多模型 但是 我们会强调
extensively in the matrix factorization course is matrix factorization.
在矩阵因式分解课程中强调的是 因式分解
And matrix factorization has some set of parameters.
矩阵因式分解有很多组参数
W hat, which are the estimated parameters, or
w帽 他们是预测的参数
that notation represents estimated parameters.
就是表达预测参数的一个符号
And what are the parameters of matrix factorization?
那什么是矩阵因式分解的参数呢
Well, it's a set of features for every user.
包含了每个用户的特征
And it's a set of features for every product.
还有每个产品的特征
Okay, so these are our parameters, but
这就是我们的参数
we also talked about a featurized version of matrix factorization.
我们也提到了矩阵因式分解 的
So in that case, in addition to our features
在这个例子中 除了
being the user ID and product ID, we might also consider other things,
我们用户ID 和产品ID 这些特征 我们可能会考虑到别的特征
we might have a list of other features like the age of the user,
比如说用户年龄
the gender of the user, a description of the product, and so on.
用户性别 产品描述 等等特征
And in that case, we would also add weights on these features.
在这个例子中 我们可能会考虑对这些特征增加权重
So let me just add some extra set of,
我会加入另外一个特征集
I'll call them w0 to make it difference than this w,
假设是w0 这样能和w有所区分
some other set of weights here that are also parameters of this model.
权重的特征集也会变成这个模型的参数
Okay, again we'll get into this in a lot more detail in the course on this, but
我们会在这个课程中深入研究这些
the idea is we're gonna take our predicted rating and
但是目标是 我们将会用我们预期的评分
we're gonna see how well our model is fitting the data.
然后看模型能够很好地拟合数据
And the way we're gonna do that is we're gonna take our actual data,
我们所做的就是用实际的数据
our real ratings, so these are actual
实际的评分
ratings that are in our training data set.
这些在我们的训练数据集中
And we're gonna compare to the predicted ratings.
然后与预测的评分所比较
Okay, so one metric we talked about to measure the air between the predicted
所以说 我们提到过一种能够衡量
ratings and our actual observed ratings was residual sum of squares.
预测评分和实际评分之间的误差方法 是残差平方和
Just like in regression, but there are also other metrics we could consider and
就像在回归中一样 这里还有一些别的衡量方法
we could talk about those more later.
我们以后可能会说到
But the point is that from some notion of error between our predicted values and
重点是通过某些能够反映出 预测值和实际值之间的误差的手段
our observed values, we're gonna have some machine learning algorithm.
来完成我们的机器学习的算法
Again, we're leaving this for
我们会把这个留到
the actual module on matrix factorization to describe what this algorithm is.
之后的矩阵因式分解部分详细讨论 具体算法是什么
But what it's going to do is it's going to iteratively update our features for
它所做的大概是不断地重复更新我们用户和产品的特征
the user and for the product until we get good agreement between our predicted
直到能够得到一个良好的预测
ratings and our actual observed ratings.
使得预测值和真实值没有太大的误差
Okay, so in this module you learned how to do collaborative filtering in practice, so
在这个模块中你会学习到协同过滤
now you can go out actually implement a recommender system.
这样你就能完善你的推荐系统
You can do a gift recommender for your family,
你可以给你的家庭做一个礼物推荐系统
which will make holiday shopping really easy.
让节日购物变得更简单
Or you can build a new song recommender that's even better than the one that we
或者你可以给你朋友做一个音乐推荐系统
demoed.
就像我们之前试做的一样
So lots and lots of cool things you can do with collaborative filtering.
反正协同过滤系统可以帮助你做很多酷酷的事情
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community